There is love and betrayal,
greed and murder.
It's set in this interesting
world of contrasting ideology,
of what's right and wrong.
It has a great philosophy about it.
"Game of Thrones" is about power struggles
in a fantasy kingdom, called Westeros.
And it's a power struggle
for the Iron Throne,
which is the seat of power
in this kingdom.
There's a war coming, Ned.
I don't know when, I don't know who
would be fighting, but it's coming.
At the core of it there's a conflict for
power between two great houses initially.
House Stark and House Lannister.
The other major houses are
all contenders as well.
It's a suitably complicated
political situation.
The old truth "the power corrupts",
I think
it's very valid and it
shows in this series.
You see characters come into
power and how they change.
In a way it's about how people
forget to see the bigger picture,
this common threat, that everybody
kind of ignores, because they're too busy
pursuing their own interests.
And meanwhile, outside the Seven
Kingdoms, two great threats arising.
One across the sea, in the exile
Targaryen siblings,
and another far to the north,
beyond the Wall,
which is the boundary
of the Seven Kingdoms,
in lands of perpetual ice and cold,
where supernatural threat is stirring.
It's very different from
anything that's been done.
I can't think of another fantasy
which is as dark as this one is,
which is as gritty and as real.
Every single character
is incredibly complex.
You think you know them.
You think you got them pegged as what
they seemingly are but they really aren't.
Is there someone in your service
whom you trust completely?
Yes.
The wiser answer was "no", my lord.
It's not a good guys/bad guys story.
It's a story where everybody is
pursuing their own interests
and everybody's following their own
code and it's about those interests
and those ethics coming into
conflict with each other.
And it provides a much richer story
than the guys in white
beating the guys in black.
Lord Baelish, perhaps
I was wrong to distrust you.
Distrusting me was the wisest thing you've
done since you climbed off your horse.
It's quite big sprawling epic story and...
and fascinating characters, different
characters, very rich, so tasty characters
you don't know who they are
or how they fit in.
Surely we are here, my lord.
- There is no telling who has eyes as well.
- Let them look.
So I find it very dense
and multilayered.
That's what I find intriguing,
fascinating in this thing.
Ned Stark is the center of the series.
It's very realistic,
quite pragmatic character.
This is fine work.
It's not for sale.
- His lordship wants the helmet.
- I made it for me.
Forgive him, my Lord.
There's nothing to forgive.
He's principled, he has values, and
above all he's very loyal, you know and...
that's something that he
demonstrates on many occasions.
You help me win the Iron Throne,
then help me keep the thing.
We were meant to rule together.
Ned is the Lord of Winterfell.
And he is married to Catelyn Tully.
Together they have a
number of children.
17 years ago you rode off with
Robert Baratheon,
you came back a year
later with another woman's son.
Jon Snow is of an age with Robb, the eldest
son, and they're closest brothers.
I would say Jon Snow is a
young hero in a lot of ways.
Well, lord Snow, it appears you're
the least useless person here.
Personally I think there's a
hell of a lot of inner turmoil
fighting between his ambition to be
someone and to make a mark on things.
I'm ready.
You're not going. You're no ranger, Jon.
Here a man gets what he earns.
When you earn it.
His ambition can and does make
him do quite extreme things.
The Lannisters
are the Queen's family.
Robert Baratheon, the King, wed the daughter
of another great house, Cersei Lannister.
She is the Queen of
the Seven Kingdoms.
She's quite tricky.
Layered. And power-mad.
She's smart and political and has
a hard time trusting anyone.
You're just a soldier, aren't you?
You take your orders
and you carry on.
I was also trained to kill
my enemies, your grace.
As was I.
There is a definitive sense with Cersei
that *** fit *** will further her game of power
She'll get rid of anybody.
It doesn't really matter.
Jaime, her twin brother is one of
the members of the King's Guard.
It would be good to
have you on the field.
Ambition has become a bit stale.
I don't fight in tournaments.
I just wanna fight a man for real.
I don't want him to
know what I can do.
He is a soldier and he doesn't
care about the politics.
He knows the game and doesn't
want to be directly involved.
Cersei and Jaime also have
another brother, Tyrion Lannister.
Tyrion Lannister, because of his size,
has had a very complicated upbringing
in relation to
his father and his sister.
He is very well-read, he has zero
powers with physical defenses.
So he has to defend himself
with his wit and charm.
Why do you read so much?
Look at me and tell me
what you see.
Is this a trick?
What you see is a dwarf.
My brother has a sword
and I have my mind.
And a mind needs books
like a sword needs a whetstone.
There's a set of characters
that you also encounter who are
crossed narrow sea and are
in an entirely different conflict.
May I present my honored guests?
Viserys of House Targaryen,
the rightful king of the Andals and
his sister Daenerys of House Targaryen.
He's the man on a mission.
He's fairly obsessive about one thing,
which is regaining his crown.
When they write the history of my reign,
sweet sister, they will say it began today.
He's very bitter, and resentful
to people who took it from him.
And he carries a huge burden.
His sister is a Daenerys Targaryen.
Also known as Daenerys Stormborn.
Tell them to stop.
You want the entire horde to stop?
For how long?
Until I command them otherwise.
She gives them such a journey.
She gets put up with a lot of
obstacles coming her way and
every time she overcomes them,
she succeeds and she kind of
gets stronger and stronger. She goes on.
She's an incredibly... incredibly
wicked person.
There are plots within plots
and wheels within wheels and
many people competing
for one seat.
Going into this story it's been very
important to us
that things never look fake.
For us it's about creating a world and making
it an authentic and believable world,
but it's not our world.
We were lucky enough to have the help
of a tremendously gifted art department.
I'm responsible for
the look of the show.
From the colors of
the floor to the sky.
What now what we see
is going to be
the whole look of it
from there downwards so
we have a complete
look to the series.
You have to create a world
from scratch that feels like
you're in a different time and
place so it's creating different
environments that work that
feel real but don't feel like
contemporary or known periods,
that's the main thing.
The biggest challenges have been
I guess the scale of the event.
We've created very high
standards for ourselves.
There are a lot of bits and a
lot of stuff to pull together.
Jenna Jackson really
range far and wide
to find the artistic resources
and the stylistic resources,
to give us a world
we haven't seen before.
There's an arctic wasteland,
which is very far north
and you go all the way to a
more desert wilderness
and everything in between.
Our brief was to try to combine
interesting visual elements
from a lot of different
societies and periods.
So we spend a lot of time
researching... medieval Europe,
we looked at oriental influences,
we looked at Asian influences,
we looked at subcontinent,
we looked at African influences.
We tried to find references
from a lot of different civilizations
and different times
and combine them.
You try to create a
world that's based in
real physics,
even if it's fantasy.
There has to be a reality to it.
To go forward we look just like a set
so always try to think...
How would these people live?
What would the need?
Why would they put things...
where they do?
How would it be?
I think the approach we
want to take is that yes,
it is fantasy but it's
very grounded in reality
and I think we want to make it
as real as possible.
And that's the same approach
we are taking with everything
and I think as the series goes on,
you'll see the great...
Differences between the four worlds
what the series inhabit.
It's very important to have
a complete different look,
and light be different
and the topography.
We've been given the luxury of
being able to span various countries.
So we've scouted probably,
I don't know, 14 different countries
when we were trying to
decide where to shoot
and why ultimately we decided
to shoot northern Ireland.
We drive 25 minutes and you're
at some beautiful forest somewhere.
And you drive 45 minutes and
you're at this great old castle.
It's a huge scale shooting
simultaneously in two different countries.
Malta and Ireland. It`s a challenge,
but it's great fun.
We love it.
One of fun things about this show
that we get to make it up.
We're not cueing to any particular
historical period absolutely.
This a fantasy series
and it gives us a
lot of freedom and
that's part of the fun of it.
Fantasy is always bigger.
I mean, fantasy is larger
and more colorful
and more exciting than history.
So you take your inspiration from
something in history you make it
much bigger and perhaps more dramatic.
It's just the best story,
it's fascinating and
there are so many twists
and turns and
when you think you
have it figured it completely
it changes its mind.
You follow it and get excited by it.
This real emotion and this...
real relationships that you
can understand and relate.
It's just brilliant.
It's a wonderful story.
It's an interesting
combination of a very
real world with an
overlay of fantasy.
It's a pretty intriguing
combination, and I think
it's something that you see nowhere
else on television currently.
I don't think anybody will do it
quite the way HBO does.
What do you know about fear?
Fear is for the winter.
when the snows fall
a hundred feet deep.
Fear is for the long night,
when the white walkers
rove through the woods.
When the sun hides for years.
And children are born and live
and die all in darkness.
That is the time for fear, my lord.