Little Theon! Come and get her.
It's an invitation...
to King's Landing.
You will represent my interests
at this gathering
as you see them.
It's not safe leaving you
with Littlefinger.
She's your sister.
Arya would never betray
her family.
She would if she thought
I was going to betray Jon.
With the faces,
I can become someone else.
I wonder what it would feel like
to be the Lady of Winterfell.
All I'd need to find out...
is your face.
Daenerys will win this war.
If you want Cersei
to bend the knee,
you can ask her yourself.
She has
a more important request.
Cersei thinks the army
of the dead is nothing
but a story.
What if we prove her wrong?
Bring the dead to her.
Go!
We are going to destroy
the Night King and his army.
Thank you, my queen.
-Oil?
- Pitch, my lord.
- How many barrels?
- 500, my lord.
Get 500 more.
Yes, my lord.
I still enjoy it
when they call me "my lord."
The thrill will fade.
If we live that long.
Men without cocks.
You wouldn't find me
fighting in an army
if I had no cock.
What's left
to fight for?
Gold?
I spent my life
around soldiers.
What do you think
they spend that gold on?
Family.
Not without a cock,
you don't.
Maybe it really is
all cocks in the end.
Yet, your brother
has chosen to side
with the cockless.
Yes, he's always been
a champion of the downtrodden.
-
I think we're about to be
the downtrodden.
Archers, stand tall!
-
- Man #Cover that wall!
- How many people live here?
- A million, give or take.
That's more people
than the entire North
crammed into that.
Why would anyone
want to live that way?
There's more work
in the city.
And the brothels
are far superior.
Why isn't she with them?
I'm afraid I don't know,
Your Grace.
No one has seen her.
And the rest of them?
They're on their way
to the Dragonpit now.
Including our brother?
Yes, Your Grace.
If anything goes wrong,
kill the silver-haired
bitch first,
then our brother,
then the bastard who
calls himself king.
The rest of them you can kill
in any order you see fit.
Come, Ser Gregor.
It's time for us
to meet our guests.
Why did they build it?
Dragons don't understand
the difference
between what is theirs
and what isn't.
Land, livestock,
children...
Letting them roam free
around a city was a problem.
I imagine it was
a sad joke at the end.
An entire arena
for a few sickly creatures
smaller than dogs.
But in the beginning,
when it was home to
Balerion the Dread,
it must have been
the most dangerous
place in the world.
Maybe it still is.
Welcome, my lords.
Your friends arrived
before you did.
I've been sent
to escort you all
to the meeting.
A pleasant surprise
in an unpleasant situation.
I never thought
I'd see you again,
my lord.
Supporting the enemy,
no less.
- Hard to blame you.
- Cersei will anyway.
I'm glad you're alive.
Come on!
You can suck
his magic cock later.
What's in there?
Fuck off.
I thought
you were dead.
Not yet.
You came pretty close.
I was only trying
to protect her.
You and me both.
She's alive.
Arya.
- Where?
- Winterfell.
Who's protecting her
if you're here?
The only one
that needs protecting
is the one that gets
in her way.
It won't be me.
Here we are--
the heroes
of Blackwater Bay.
Strange place
for a reunion.
It is, my lord.
I don't think
I'm anyone's lord
anymore, Podrick.
Save the titles for
Ser Bronn of the Blackwater.
I'm sure your new queen
will be happy to
restore yours
if she ends up
on the throne.
You've been thinking
about our new queen?
Perhaps you've
been reconsidering
your allegiances.
Remember my offer--
whatever
they're paying you,
I'll pay double.
And that would be
double what now, exactly?
Don't you worry about me.
I'm doing all right.
- Looking after myself.
-Are you?
Helping me to arrange
this meeting
wasn't exactly looking
after yourself, was it?
You put yourself
at risk.
I put yourself at risk.
Important difference.
It's your head Queen Cersei's
offered a bag of gold for,
it's not mine.
Now, thanks to me,
she's got two traitors' heads
coming right through her door.
She can lop them both off
as soon as she gets tired
of the clever words that
pour out their pieholes.
All thanks to Ser Bronn
of the fucking Blackwater.
If that's not
looking after myself,
I don't know what is.
It's good
to see you again.
Yeah, you, too.
Anyone touches it,
I'll kill you first.
Come on, Pod.
Let's you and me
go have a drink
while the fancy folks
talk, eh?
I left this shit city
because I didn't
want to die in it.
Am I going to die
in this shit city?
You might.
And this is all
your idea.
Seems every bad idea
has some Lannister cunt
behind it.
And some Clegane cunt
to help them see it through.
Remember me?
Yeah, you do.
You're even fucking
uglier than I am now.
What did they do
to you?
Doesn't matter.
That's not how it ends
for you, brother.
You know who's
coming for you.
You've always known.
Where is she?
She'll be here soon.
Didn't travel with you?
No.
-
We've been here
for some time.
My apologies.
We are all
facing a unique--
Theon!
I have your sister.
If you don't submit
to me here, now...
I'll kill her.
I think we ought to begin
with larger concerns.
Then why
are you talking?
You're the smallest
concern here.
Do you remember
when we discussed
dwarf jokes?
His wasn't even good.
He explained it
at the end.
Never explain.
It always ruins it.
We don't even
let your kind live
in the Iron Islands,
you know?
We kill you at birth.
An act of mercy
for the parents.
Perhaps you ought
to sit down.
Why?
Sit down or leave.
We are a group of people
who do not like one another,
as this recent
demonstration has shown.
We have suffered
at each other's hands.
We have lost people we love
If all we wanted
was more of the same,
there would be no need
for this gathering.
We are entirely capable
of waging war against
each other
without meeting
face-to-face.
So instead,
we should settle
our differences
and live together in harmony
for the rest of our days?
We all know
that will never happen.
Then why are we here?
This isn't about
living in harmony.
It's just
about living.
The same thing
is coming for all of us.
A general you can't
negotiate with.
An army that doesn't
leave corpses behind
on the battlefield.
Lord Tyrion tells me
a million people live
in this city.
They're about to become
a million more soldiers
in the Army of the Dead.
I imagine for most of them
it would be an improvement.
This is serious.
I wouldn't be here
if it weren't.
I don't think
it's serious at all.
I think it's
another bad joke.
If my brother Jaime
has informed me correctly,
you're asking me
for a truce.
Yes.
That's all.
That's all?
Pull back my armies
and stand down
while you go
on your monster hunt.
Or while you solidify
and expand your position.
Hard for me
to know which it is
with my armies pulled back
until you return
and march on my  capital
with four times the men.
Your capital will be safe
until the northern threat
is dealt with.
You have my word.
The word of
a would-be usurper.
There is no conversation
that will erase
the last 50 years.
We have something
to show you.
We can destroy them
by burning them.
And we can destroy them
with dragonglass.
If we don't win
this fight,
then that is the fate
of every person in the world.
There is only one war
that matters--
the Great War.
And it is here.
I didn't believe it
until I saw them.
I saw them all.
How many?
A hundred thousand,
at least.
Can they swim?
No.
Good.
I'm taking the Iron Fleet
back to the Iron Islands.
What are you
talking about?
I've been
around the world.
I've seen everything,
things you couldn't imagine,
and this...
this is the only thing
I've ever seen that
terrifies me.
I'm going back
to my island.
You should go
back to yours.
When winter's over,
we'll be the only ones
left alive.
He's right to be afraid.
And a coward to run.
If those things
come for us,
there will be
no kingdoms to rule.
Everything we suffered
will have been for nothing.
Everything we lost
The crown accepts
your truce.
Until the dead are defeated,
they are the true enemy.
In return,
the King in the North
will extend this truce.
He will remain in the North
where he belongs.
He will not take up arms
against the Lannisters.
He will not
choose sides.
Just the King
in the North?
- Not me?
-
I would never
ask it of you.
You would never
agree to it.
And if you did,
I would trust you
even less than I do now.
I ask it only
of Ned Stark's son.
I know Ned Stark's son
will be true to his word.
I am true to my word.
Or I try to be.
That is why
I cannot give you
what you ask.
I cannot serve
two queens.
And I have already
pledged myself
to Queen Daenerys
of House Targaryen.
Then there is
nothing left to discuss.
The dead will come north first.
Enjoy dealing with them.
We will deal with
whatever is left of you.
Ser Jaime.
It's been good
to see you.
I imagine the next time
will be across a battlefield.
We both saw
what just happened.
that... thing.
Yes, and I'm not
looking forward to
seeing more of them.
But I'm loyal
to the queen,
and you're loyal to Sansa
and her dolt brother.
Oh, fuck loyalty!
Fuck loyalty?
This goes beyond houses
and honor and oaths.
Talk to the queen.
And tell her what?
I wish you hadn't
done that.
I'm grateful
for your loyalty,
but my dragon died
so that we could be here.
If it's all for nothing,
then he died
for nothing.
I know!
I'm pleased
you bent the knee
to our queen.
I would
have advised it,
had you asked.
But have you
ever considered
learning how to lie
every now and then?
Just a bit?
I'm not going to swear
an oath I can't uphold.
Talk about my father
if you want,
tell me that's the attitude
that got him killed.
But when enough people
make false promises,
words stop meaning
anything.
Then there
are no more answers,
only better and better lies.
And lies won't help us
in this fight.
That is indeed a problem.
The more immediate problem
is that we're fucked.
Any ideas
as to how we might
change that state
of affairs?
Only one.
Everyone stays here,
and I go and talk
to my sister.
I didn't come all this way
to have my Hand murdered.
I don't want Cersei
to murder me either.
I could have stayed in my cell
and saved a great deal
of trouble.
I did this.
- I should go.
- She'll definitely
murder you.
I go see
my sister alone.
Or we all go home
and we're right back
where we started.
- You spoke with her?
- At her until she
kicked me out.
She thinks
I was an idiot
to trust you.
A lot of people
seem to think that,
actually.
I'm about to step
into a room
with the most murderous
woman in the world
who's already tried
to kill me twice,
that I know of.
Who's an idiot?
I suppose we should
say goodbye,
one idiot to another.
I shouldn't
be surprised,
I suppose.
She's your kind
of woman--
a foreign whore
who doesn't know
her place.
A foreign whore
you can't abduct,
beat, or intimidate.
That must be
difficult for you.
So you bring her here
with her pet Northerner,
- whom you've convinced
to bow down before her.
- I didn't know about that.
And now you've got them both
working towards the same goal,
the goal
you've worked towards
your entire life...
- Cersei, I didn't know.
- ...the destruction
of this family.
I am the one
preventing that
from happening.
Daenerys didn't want
to debate and negotiate.
She didn't want
to bring you words.
She wanted to bring you
fire and blood
until I advised her
otherwise.
I don't want
to destroy our family.
I never have.
You killed our father.
After he sentenced me
to death
for a crime
I didn't commit,
yes, I killed him.
Hate me for it
if you want.
I hate myself for it
in spite of what he was,
in spite of
what he did to me.
Oh, poor little man.
Your papa
was mean to you.
Do you have any idea
what you did when you
fired that crossbow?
You left us open.
You laid us bare
for the vultures,
and the vultures came
and tore us apart.
You may not
have killed Joffrey,
but you killed Myrcella,
you killed Tommen.
No one would've touched them
if Father was here.
- No one would have dared--
- I have never been more sorry
about anything.
I will not hear it,
not from you.
I will not hear it!
All right.
You love your family,
and I have
destroyed it.
I will always
be a threat.
So put an end to me.
If it weren't for me,
you'd have a mother.
you'd have a father.
If it weren't for me,
you'd have
two beautiful children.
I've thought
about killing you
more times
than I can count.
Do it!
Say the word.
I am more sorry
about the children
than you could ever know.
- I will not--
- I don't care.
I loved them.
You know I did.
You know it in your heart
if there's anything
left of it.
It doesn't matter.
Your love doesn't matter.
Your feelings don't matter.
I don't care
why you did what you did.
I only care
what it cost us.
It cost us our future.
If there's no future,
then why are we here?
Why did you
allow me to come?
Not to help my enemies
collaborate in my destruction.
Yes, no,
not what you hoped for,
but you must have
hoped for something.
What did you hope for?
- To make Jon Snow
submit to your queen?
- Mm, not like this.
But eventually,
you want everyone
to bend the knee to her.
- Yes.
- Why?
Because I think
she will make the world
a better place.
You said she'd destroy
King's Landing.
She knows herself.
She chose an advisor
who would check
her worst impulses
instead of feeding them.
That's the difference
between you.
I don't care about
checking my worst impulses.
making the world
a better place.
Hang the world.
That thing
you dragged here,
I know what it is,
I know what it means.
And when it came at me,
I didn't think about
the world.
Not at all.
As soon as
it opened its mouth,
the world
disappeared for me,
right down
its black throat.
All I could think about
was keeping those
gnashing teeth
away from the ones
who matter most,
away from my family.
Maybe Euron Greyjoy
had the right idea.
Get on a boat,
take those who matter--
You're pregnant.
No one is less happy
about this than I am.
I know.
I respect
what you did.
Wish you hadn't done it,
but I respect it.
This place was the beginning
of the end for my family.
A dragon
is not a slave.
They were terrifying.
Extraordinary.
They filled people
with wonder and awe,
and we locked them
in here.
They wasted away.
They grew small.
And we grew small
as well.
We weren't extraordinary
without them.
We were just like
everyone else.
You're not like
And your family
hasn't seen its end.
You're still here.
I can't
have children.
Who told you that?
The witch who
murdered my husband.
Has it occurred to you
she might not have been
a reliable source
of information?
You were right
from the beginning.
If I had trusted you,
everything would
be different.
So, what now?
I can't forget what I saw
north of the Wall.
And I can't pretend
that Cersei
won't take back
half the country
the moment I march north.
It appears
Tyrion's assessment
was correct.
We're fucked.
My armies will not
stand down.
I will not pull them
back to the capital.
I will march them north
to fight alongside you
in the Great War.
The darkness
is coming for us all.
We'll face it together.
And when
the Great War is over,
perhaps you'll remember
I chose to help
with no promises
or assurances from
any of you.
I expect not.
Call our banners.
All of them.
-
It's not easy for ravens
to fly in these storms.
Perhaps Jon tried
to send word earlier.
No, this is
the way he is,
the way
he's always been.
He never asked for my opinion.
Why would he start now?
I can't believe he'd
surrender the Northern crown
without consulting you.
This is his writing,
his signature.
He pledged to fight
for Daenerys Targaryen.
He's bent the knee.
I've heard gossip
that the Dragon Queen
is quite beautiful.
What does that have to do
with anything?
Jon is young
and unmarried.
Daenerys is young
You think he wants
to marry her?
An alliance
makes sense.
Together, they'd be
difficult to defeat.
He was named
King in the North.
He can be unnamed.
Even if I wanted to,
Arya would never go along.
She always loved Jon
far more than she ever
loved me,
and she'd kill anyone
who betrayed her family.
You are family, too.
Would Arya really murder
her own sister?
Do you know
what she is now?
Do you know what
the Faceless Men are?
Only by reputation.
They worship
the God of Death,
I believe.
I never trust
godly men.
They're killers.
And Arya
was one of them.
What do you think
she's after?
She's your sister.
You know her far better
than I ever could.
Sometimes
when I try to understand
a person's motives,
I play a little game.
I assume the worst.
What's the worst reason
they could possibly have
for saying what they say
and doing what they do?
Then I ask myself,
"How well does
that reason explain
what they say
and what they do?"
So, tell me--
what's the worst thing
she could want?
She could
want me dead
because she thinks
I wronged my family.
Why did she come
to Winterfell?
To kill me
for marrying our enemies
and betraying my family.
Why did
she unearth the letter
Cersei made you write?
To provide proof
of my betrayals.
To provide justification
after she murders me.
And after
she murders you,
what does she become?
Lady of Winterfell.
If we have the Dothraki
ride hard on the kingsroad,
they'll arrive at Winterfell
within the fortnight.
And the Unsullied?
We can sail with them
to White Harbor,
meet the Dothraki here
on the kingsroad,
then ride together
to Winterfell.
Perhaps you should fly
to Winterfell, Your Grace.
You have many enemies
in the North.
Thousands fell
fighting your father.
All it takes
is one angry man
with a crossbow.
He'll see
your silver hair
on the kingsroad
and know that
one well-placed bolt
will make him a hero.
The man who killed
the conqueror.
It's your decision,
Your Grace.
But if we're going to be
allies in this war,
it's important
for the Northerners
to see us as allies.
If we sail
to White Harbor together,
I think it sends
a better message.
I've not come
to conquer the North.
I'm coming to save
the North.
We sail together.
Jon.
Can I speak
with you?
All right.
What you did
in King's Landing,
what you said...
you could've
lied to Cersei
about bending the knee
to Daenerys.
You risked everything
to tell an enemy the truth.
We went down there
to make peace.
And it seems to me
we need to be honest
with each other
if we're going
to fight together.
You've always known
what was right.
Even when we were all
young and stupid,
you always knew.
Every step you take...
it's always
the right step.
It's not.
It may seem that way
from the outside,
but I promise you,
it's not true.
I've done
plenty of things
that I regret.
Not compared to me,
you haven't.
No.
Not compared to you.
I always wanted
to do the right thing.
Be the right
kind of person.
But I never knew
what that meant.
It always seemed
like there's...
like there was
an impossible choice
I had to make.
Stark or Greyjoy.
Our father was
more of a father to you
than yours ever was.
- He was.
- And you betrayed him.
Betrayed his memory.
I did.
But you never
lost him.
He's a part of you.
Just like
he's a part of me.
But the things
I've done...
It's not my place
to forgive you
for all of it.
But what I can
forgive,
I do.
You don't need
to choose.
You're a Greyjoy...
and you're a Stark.
When I was
Ramsay's prisoner,
Yara tried
to save me.
She's the only one
who tried to save me.
She needs me now.
So, why are you
still talking to me?
Load up.
Load up, lads.
Go on.
-
- Tide's coming in.
All of us chose
to follow Yara.
We left
the Iron Islands
for Yara.
She would never
leave one of us behind.
We're not
leaving her behind.
Your sister's dead.
- She's not dead.
- She's dead.
Even if Euron hasn't
cut her throat yet,
she's dead.
- She's our queen.
- She's your sister,
and you left her to die.
I did.
I ran from my uncle.
I was a coward.
So, why in fuck's name
should we listen to you?
They say the dead
can't swim.
We're going
to sail east,
find a nice,
quiet island,
kill all the men,
and take their wives
for ourselves.
- We're done with all that.
- Who says we are?
Yara did.
She made a pledge.
We're going
to find her,
and we're going
to set her free.
-
Run away,
little Theon.
It's what
you do best.
He needs to shut
his mouth.
-Hey!
-
- Man #Oh, yes!
- Man #
That's more like it.
-
Stay down...
or I'll kill you!
I said stay down
Not for me.
For Yara!
Yara!
Have my sister brought
to the Great Hall.
Are you sure
you want to do this?
It's not what I want.
It's what honor demands.
And what does
honor demand?
That I defend my family
from those who would harm us.
That I defend the North
from those who would
betray us.
All right, then.
Get on with it.
You stand accused
of murder.
of treason.
How do you answer
these charges...
Lord Baelish?
My sister asked you
a question.
Lady Sansa,
forgive me...
I'm a bit confused.
Which charges
confuse you?
Let's start with
the simplest one--
you murdered our aunt,
Lysa Arryn.
You pushed her
through the Moon Door
and watched her fall.
Do you deny it?
I did it
to protect you.
You did it
to take power
in the Vale.
Earlier, you conspired
to murder Jon Arryn.
You gave Lysa Tears of Lys
to poison him.
Do you deny it?
Whatever your aunt
might have told you...
she was
a troubled woman.
She imagined enemies
everywhere.
You had Aunt Lysa send
a letter to our parents
telling them
it was the Lannisters
who murdered Jon Arryn
when, really,
it was you.
The conflict between
the Starks and the Lannisters,
it was you
who started it.
Do you deny it?
I know
of no such letter.
You conspired
with Cersei Lannister
and Joffrey Baratheon
to betray our father,
Ned Stark.
Thanks to your treachery,
he was imprisoned
and later executed
on false charges
of treason.
- Do you deny it?
- I deny it!
None of you were there
to see what happened.
None of you
knows the truth.
You held a knife
to his throat.
You said,
"I did warn you
not the trust me."
You told our mother
this knife belonged
to Tyrion Lannister.
But that was another
one of your lies.
It was yours.
Lady Sansa,
I have known you
since you were a girl.
- I've protected you.
- Protected me?
By selling me
to the Boltons?
If we could
speak alone,
I can explain
everything.
Sometimes when
I'm trying to understand
a person's motives,
I play a little game.
I assume the worst.
What's the worst
reason you have
for turning me
against my sister?
That's what you do,
isn't it?
That's what
you've always done--
turn family
against family,
turn sister
against sister.
That's what you did
to our mother and Aunt Lysa,
and that's what
you tried to do to us.
Sansa, please.
I'm a slow learner,
it's true.
But I learn.
Give me a chance
to defend myself.
I deserve that.
I am Lord Protector
of the Vale
and I command you
to escort me safely
back to the Eyrie.
I think not.
Sansa, I beg you!
I loved your mother
since the time
I was a boy.
And yet,
you betrayed her.
I loved you.
More than anyone.
And yet,
you betrayed me.
When you brought me
back to Winterfell,
you told me
there's no justice
in the world,
not unless
we make it.
Thank you for all
your many lessons,
Lord Baelish.
I will never
forget them.
Sansa!
I...
Our men in King's Landing
will march north
in three days' time.
It'll take us
a fortnight
just to gather supplies
for the train.
We don't have
a fortnight.
If the North falls, we fall.
Three days.
The remaining forces
in the Westerlands
will take
the river road east.
We'll meet at
Lord Harroway's Town
and march together
to Winterfell.
Ser Jaime.
Your Grace.
My lords,
I need a moment
with my brother.
Your Grace.
- What are you doing?
- Preparing the expedition
north.
Expedition north?
I always knew you were
the stupidest Lannister.
The Starks and Targaryens
have united against us,
and you want to fight
alongside them?
Are you a traitor
or an idiot?
You pledged our forces
to fight our common enemy--
I'll say whatever
I need to say
to ensure the survival
of our house.
You expect me
to trust the man
who murdered our father?
You expect me
to command our troops
to fight beside foreign scum,
to fight for
the Dragon Queen?
You saw it
with your own eyes.
You saw a dead man
trying to kill us.
I saw it burn.
If dragons
can't stop them,
if Dothraki and Unsullied
and Northmen can't stop them,
how will our armies
make a difference?
This isn't about
noble houses,
this is about
the living and the dead!
And I intend to stay
amongst the living.
Let the Stark boy
and his new queen
defend the North.
We stay here
where we've always been.
I made a promise.
Our child
will rule Westeros.
Our child will never be born
if the dead come south.
The monsters are real.
The white walkers,
the dragons,
the Dothraki screamers--
all the frightening stories
we heard when we were young,
they're all real.
So be it.
Let the monsters
kill each other.
And while they battle
in the North,
we take back the lands
that belong to us.
- And then what?
- And then we rule.
When the fighting
in the North is over,
someone wins.
You understand that,
don't you?
If the dead win,
they march south
and kill us all.
If the living win,
and we've betrayed them,
they march south
and kill us all!
The Targaryens and the Starks
already want to kill us all.
Most of them
will die in the North.
I faced them
in the field.
We can't beat them.
We can't beat their dragons.
How many dragons
did you see at the pit?
- Two.
- What happened
to the third?
For all we know,
it's guarding her fleet!
She came here
with her dragons and her
Dothraki and her Unsullied.
She came here to show us
all her power.
No, something happened.
The dragons are vulnerable.
We can't beat the Dothraki.
We don't have the numbers.
We don't have the support
of the other houses!
No, we have something better.
We have the Iron Bank.
You should've listened more
when Father spoke about
the importance of gold.
Oh, I know
it's boring for you.
You just wanted to hunt
and ride and fight.
But I listened,
I learned.
Highgarden bought us
the most powerful army
in Essos--
the Golden Company.
20,000 men, horses,
elephants, I believe.
The Golden Company
is not here.
They're in Essos.
How is a mercenary company
in Essos going to help us?
Do you really think
Euron Greyjoy turned tail
and sailed back
to the Iron Islands?
Do you think
he abandoned
the chance to marry
the queen?
No one walks away
from me.
He's sailing with
his fleet to Essos.
He's going to ferry
the Golden Company back here
to help us win
the war for Westeros.
You plotted
with Euron Greyjoy
without telling me,
the commander
of your armies?
And you conspired
with Tyrion,
the man who murdered
our father,
without telling me,
your queen.
I didn't conspire
with him.
You met with him in secret
without my consent.
You planned to promote
my enemies' interests.
That  is the definition
of conspiracy.
I pledged
to ride north.
I intend to honor
that pledge.
- And that
will be treason.
- Treason?
Disobeying
your queen's command,
fighting with her enemies.
What would you
call it?
Doesn't matter
what I'd call it.
I told you no one
walks away from me.
Are you going to
order him to kill me?
I'm the only one
you have left.
Our children are gone,
our father is gone.
It's just
me and you now.
There's one more
yet to come.
Give the order, then.
I don't
believe you.
-
- Come in.
Samwell Tarly.
I wasn't sure
if you'd remember me.
I remember everything.
You helped us
get beyond the Wall.
- You're a good man.
- Oh, well, thank you,
but, um, I'm not sure
that I am.
What happened to you
beyond the Wall?
I became
the Three-Eyed Raven.
Oh!
I don't know
what that means.
I can see things
that happened in the past.
happening now
all over the world.
Why did you come
to Winterfell?
Um...
Jon's the one to lead
the fight against the dead.
I know he is.
But he can't
do it alone,
so I've come here
to help him.
He's on his way
back to Winterfell
with Daenerys Targaryen.
You--
you saw this in--
in a vision?
Oh.
He needs to know
the truth.
The truth
about what?
About himself.
No one knows.
No one but me.
Jon isn't really
my father's son.
He's the son
of Rhaegar Targaryen
and my aunt, Lyanna Stark.
He was born
in a tower in Dorne.
His last name
isn't really Snow,
it's Sand.
It's not.
Dornish bastards
are named Sand.
At the Citadel, I transcribed
a High Septon's diary.
He annulled Rhaegar's
marriage to Elia.
He wed Rhaegar and Lyanna
in a secret ceremony.
Are you certain?
It's what the High Septon
wrote in his private diary.
I don't know
why he'd lie.
Is this something
you can see?
Father, Smith, Warrior,
Mother, Maiden,
Crone, Stranger.
- I am hers and she is mine...
- I am his and he is mine...
from this day
until the end of my days.
Bran'
Robert's Rebellion
was built on a lie.
Rhaegar didn't
kidnap my aunt or rape her.
He loved her.
And she loved him.
- Bran'And Jon...
-
Jon's real name...
His name
is Aegon Targaryen.
You have
to protect him.
Promise me, Ned.
Bran'
He's never been a bastard.
He's the heir to
the Iron Throne.
Bran'
He needs to know.
We need to tell him.
Are you
all right?
It's just strange.
In his own horrible way,
I believe he loved me.
You did
the right thing.
You  did it.
I'm just
the executioner.
You passed
the sentence.
You're the Lady
of Winterfell.
Does that bother you?
I was never going to be
as good a lady as you.
So I had to be
something else.
I never could have survived
what you survived.
You would have.
You're the strongest
person I know.
I believe
that's the nicest thing
you've ever said to me.
Well, don't get
used to it.
You're still
very strange
and annoying.
"In winter, we must
protect ourselves.
Look after
one another."
Father.
"When the snows fall
and the white winds blow,
the lone wolf dies,
but the pack survives."
I miss him.
Me, too.
It's a long way down.
Yeah.
The crows keep telling me
I'll get used to it.
I can see movement...
Watch, on the tree line!
Man #
What is it?
Come on!
- Run! Run!
-