Subtitle by: No One
Game of Thrones S07E043 "The Spoils of War"
Hold that wagon!
You've just won the biggest
prize in the world.
What could you possibly
have to be upset about?
Come on, you can tell me.
Queen of Thorns gave you one last prick
in the balls before saying goodbye?
I'll save my confessions
for the High Septon.
- There is no more High Septon.
- No, there isn't, is there?
There is still the question of my prize.
That's a lot of money I just gave you.
It's not a castle.
How about that one?  It's available.
You don't want Highgarden.
-I'd beg to differ.  -We're at  war.
Daenerys Targaryen could come and
take it back the day after you move in.
Besides, think of the upkeep.
The more you own, the
more it weighs you down.
Oh, is that why you're
so fucking glum, heh?
All your new riches weighing you down?
They're not mine. This all
belongs to the Iron Bank.
See?
We pay our debts.
- Right. Just not to me.
Ser Bronn of the Blackwater,
formerly Earth--
whatever name the shitheap you're from
with a saddlebag full of gold,
complaining about not getting paid.
When we win this war, all the castles in the
Seven Kingdoms will be yours to choose from
with no one left to take it away from you.
Yes, I'm sure Queen Cersei's reign
will be quiet and peaceful.
-Stranger things have happened -Like what?
The granaries are being emptied and
loaded into wagons, my Lord.
The current harvest?
We have teams of men collecting it.
Modest farms in the Reach.
Ser Bronn, will you accompany the Tarlys
and help them acellerate this process?
I'm not much for shoveling weight.
No, but motivating reluctant farmers
to hand over the harvest.
I bet you're going to have
a real talent for that.
My Lord.
I must say, I don't think the iron Bank
has ever had a debt of this magnitude
repaid in a single installment.
I always considered your father a
very effective and efficient man
but you appear to be redefining
those terms entirely.
You're too kind, my Lord.
I'm neither kind nor a Lord, Your Grace.
I'm merely the instrument of
the institution I represent.
Its well-being is a matter of
arithmetic, not sentiment.
And the current arithmetic is outstanding.
The gold ...-is on its way.
My brother is supervising
its transportation himself.
Some at the Iron Bank will be disappointed.
They've grown rather fond
of your interest payments.
We must devise a way to
raise their spirits.
Yes, perhaps we could be of
assistance in some current venture.
Our only venture this moment
is reestablishing control
over this continent
and every person on it.
I see a great deal of
potential in that venture.
I imagine it would require
outside investment.
It would, indeed.
I need to expand my armies, my navies.
My Hand, Qyburn,
has made overtures to the
Golden Company in Essos.
I know them well.
They've helped us recover
significant sums from parties
who'd fall into deep areas.
It's good to hear.
I too would like them to recover
some things that belong to me.
Rest assured, Your Grace.
You can count on the Iron Bank support...
as soon as the gold arrives.
This is for you.
The last man who wielded it
meant to cut your throat
but your mother fought him off.
The other dagger,
the one that took her life.
I would have stopped that
dagger with my own heart
if I could have.
I wasn't there for her
when she needed me most.
But I am here for her now
to do what she would have done,
to protect her children.
Anything, I can do for you, Brandon.
You need only ask.
Do you know who this belonged to?
No.
A very question was what started
the War of Five Kings
In a way, that dagger made you
what you are today.
Forced from your home, driven after
the wilds beyond the Wall.
I imagine you've seen things
most men wouldn't believe.
To go through all of that and
make your way home again only to fnd
such chaos in the world.
-I can only imagine. -Chaos is a ladder.
I'm sorry to have disturbed
you, Lord Stark.
I'm not Lord Stark.
What's that?
Maester Wolkan built it for me.
So I can move around more easily.
It's a very good idea.
You're leaving.
I don't want to leave you, but when ...
when they come, I need
to be with my family.
And you're safe.
Safest anyone can be, now.
You don't need me anymore.
No, I don't.
That's all you've got to say?
Thank you.
Thank you?
For helping me.
My brother died for you.
Hodor and Summer died for you.
I almost died for you.
Bran ...
I'm not, really.
Not anymore.
I remember what it felt
like to be Brandon Stark.
I don't remember so much else now.
You died in that cave.
[Guards chatting]
Hello. Where are you going?
In there.
-I live here. -Fuck off.
I'm Arya Stark. This is my home.
Arya Stark's dead.
Send for me Ser Luwin or Ser Rodrik.
- They'll tell you who I am.
- There's no Rodrik here.
Maester's name Wolkan.
Go ask Jon Snow then,
the King in the North.
- He's my brother.-He's
a thousand miles away.
It's cold and we're busy. So
you know, better fuck off.
If Jon's gone, who's in
charge of Winterfell?
The Lady of Winterfell?
-Lady Stark? -Which Lady Stark?
You've told us you're the one
in person and her sister.
Tell Sansa her sister's home.
Lady Sansa is too busy to
waste a breath on you.
Just like us. So for the
last time, fuck off.
I'm getting into this
castle one way or another.
If I'm not who I say I
am, I won't last long.
But if I am, and Sansa finds
out you turned me away...
All right. You sit there.
Right there.
Don't move.
Go tell Lady Stark. I'll watch her.
I ain't telling Lady Stark.
-You tell her. -I'm not.
Cause if you don't, I'm gonna hit you right
in fucking face as hard as I can.
We told her to wait.
We were standing right next to her and
- and when we turned
around, she gone m'lady.
She was nothing, some Winter Town girl.
She comes in, asking for Ser Rodrik.
and Maester Luwin . - Luwin, yeah.
And don't trouble yourself for it, m'lady.
We'll find her.
You don't have to.
I know where she is.
Do I have to call you Lady Stark, now?
Yes.
You shouldn't have run from the guards.
I didn't run.
You need better guards.
Suits you ... Lady Stark.
-Jon left you in charge? -He did.
I hope he comes back soon.
I remember how happy he was to see me.
When he sees you...
his heart will probably stop.
It doesn't look like him.
Should have been carved by
someone who knew his face.
Everyone who knew his face is dead.
We're not.
They say you killed Joffrey.
Did you?
I wish I had.
Me too.
I was angry when I heard
someone else had done it.
However long my list go,
he was always first.
-Your list? -Of people I'm going to kill.
How did you get back to Winterfell?
It's a long story. I imagine yours is too.
Yes.
Not a very pleasant one.
Mine neither.
But our stories aren't over yet.
No, they're not.
Arya.
Bran's home, too.
You came home.
I saw you at the crossroads.
-You saw me? -I see quite a lot now.
Bran has... visions.
I thought you might go to King's Landing.
So did I.
Why would you go back there?
Cersei's on her list of names.
Who else is on your list?
Most of them are dead already.
Where did you get this?
Littlefinger gave it to me.
Littlefinger? He's here?
He's declared for House Stark.
Why would he give you a dagger?
He thought I'd want it.
-Why? -Because it was meant to kill me.
The cutthroat.
After your fall?
Why would the cutthroat has
Valyrian steel dagger?
Someone very wealthy wanted me dead.
He's not a generous man.
He wouldn't give you anything unless
he thought he was getting something back.
- It doesn't matter. -What do
you mean it doesn't matter?
I don't want it.
Are you sure?
- It's Valyrian steel.
- It's wasted on a cripple.
Catelyn Stark would be proud.
You kept your vow.
- I did next to nothing.
- You're too hard on yourself, my Lady.
I'm not a...
Thank you, Podrick.
Your Grace. There's still
no word on the Unsullied.
Soon.
He will come back to you.
He better.
What happened?
Many things.
Many things?
Your Grace.
It's all right.
I wanted you to see it before
we start hacking it to bits.
Well, this is it. All we ever need.
There is something else
I want to show you, Your Grace.
The Children of the Forest made these.
When?
A very long time ago.
They were right here, standing
where we're standing.
Before there were Targaryens,
or Starks or Lannisters.
Maybe even before there were men.
No.
They were here together,
the Children and the First Men.
Doing what? Fighting each other?
They fought together
against their common enemy.
Despite their differences,
despite their suspicions.
Together.
We need to do the same
if we're gonna survive.
Because the enemy is real.
It's always been real.
And you say you can't defeat them
without my armies and my dragons.
No, I don't think I can.
I will fight for you.
I will fight for the North.
When you bend the knee.
My people
won't accept a Southern ruler.
Not after everything they've suffered.
They will if their King does.
They chose you to lead them.
They chose you to protect them.
Isn't their survival more
important than your pride?
What is it?
We took Casterly Rock.
That's very good to hear.
Isn't it?
You'll want to discuss
this amongst yourselves.
Perhaps-- -You stay.
All my allies have gone.
They've been taken from me while
I've been sitting here on this island.
-You sill have the largest armies.
We won't be able to eat because Cersei
has taken all the food from the Reach.
Call Grey Worm and the Unsullied back.
We still have enough ships to carry
the Dothraki to the Mainland.
Commit to the blockade of King's Landing.
- We have a plan, it's still the right plan.
-The right plan?
Your strategy has lost us Dorne,
the Iron Islands and the Reach.
If I have underestimated our enemies ...
Our enemies?
Your family you mean.
Perhaps you don't want to
hurt them after all.
Enough with the clever plans.
I have three large dragons.
I'm going to fly them to the Red Keep.
We've discussed this--
My enemies are in the Red Keep.
What kind of a Queen am I if I'm
not willing to risk my life to fight them?
A smart one.
What do you think I should do?
-I would never presume ...-I'm at war.
I'm losing.
What do you think I should do?
I never thought that
dragons would exist again.
No one did.
The people who follow you
know that you made something
impossible happen.
Maybe their hopes and belief that you
can make other impossible things happen.
Build a world that's different from
the shit one they've always known.
But if you use them to mount
castles and burn cities
you're not different.
You're just more of the same.
Don't lunge.
Don't go where your enemy leads you.
Up.
- And don't ...
- Don't fight someone like her in the first place.
Nice sword.
Very nice dagger.
If they haven't contributed
the right amount of grain to the stores
then I'm afraid they'll have to make do
with what they've brought. They can't--
It's been a while since I trained.
I can go find the
Master of Arms for you, my Lady.
He didn't beat The Hound.
You did.
I want to train with you.
You swore to serve both my
mother's daughters? Didn't you?
Move aside, Podrick.
You can't use that, my Lady.
It's too small.
I won't cut you. Don't worry.
I'll try not to.
Who taught you how to do that?
No one.
-What do you think of her? -Who?
I believe you know of whom I speak.
I think she has a good heart.
A good heart?
I've noticed you
staring at her good heart.
There's no time for that.
I saw the Night King, Davos.
I looked into his eyes.
How many men do we have in
the North to fight him?
-10000? Less? -Fewer.
What?
Speaking of good hearts,
Missandei of Naath.
Ser Davos, Lord Snow.
King Snow. Isn't it?
No, that doesn't sound right.
-King Jon? -It doesn't matter.
Forgive me, but may I ask a question?
Of course.
Your name is Jon Snow,
but your father's name was Ned Stark.
I'm a bastard.
My mother and father weren't married.
Is the custom different in Naath?
We don't have marriage in Naath, so
the concept of a bastard doesn't exist.
That sounds ... liberating?
Why did you leave your home land?
I was stolen away by slavers.
I'm sorry.
If I may,
how did a slave girl come to advise
Daenerys Targaryen?
She bought me from my
master and set me free.
That was good of her.
Of course you're serving
her now, aren't you?
I serve my Queen because I want
to serve my Queen.
Because I believe in her.
And if you wanted to sail
home to Naath tomorrow?
Then she would give me a a ship
and wish me good fortune.
You believe that?
I know it.
All of us who came with her from Essos,
we believe in her.
She's not our Queen because she's the
daughter of some King we never knew.
She's the Queen we chose.
Will you forgive me if I switch sides?
Is that a Greyjoy ship?
Stop!
Jon.
I didn't know you were here.
Sansa ...
is she all right?
What you did for her
is the only reason I'm not killing you.
We heard your uncle attacked your fleet.
We thought you were dead.
I should be.
Your sister?
Euron has her.
I came to ask the Queen to
help me get her back.
The Queen is gone.
Where did she go?
- All the gold safely to the gates
of King's Landing. - Good.
We need to get the last of these wagons to
Blackwater Rush before nightfall.
The head of the line is ambushed, the tail
will never be able to reinforce in time.
We are stretched a bit thin.
With your permission,
flogging stragglers has a
marked effect on mobility.
Let's give them fair warning first.
These men fought well at Highgarden.
- Ser Jaime.
- Rickon.
Dickon.
I hear you fought brave near Highgarden.
First battle?
And ...?
It was glorious.
Come on! Your father is not here.
All my life, we've been
pledged to House Tyrell.
I knew some of those men, hunted with them.
They didn't deserve to die.
But Lady Olenna chose to betray her Queen
and support the Targaryen girl.
So here we are.
I didn't expect it to smell like that.
Men shit themselves when they die.
Didn't they teach you that at
fancy lad school?
I learnt it when I was five.
What?
Listen.
Spears and shields!
-What is it? -Get in line!
Get in line, now!
Line up!
Come on, lads!
Halt those wagons! Full array!
Full array!
Grab your spears!
Shield wall!
Fill the gaps!
Sit tight!
Get in line, boys!
Spears, out!
Hold the line!
Get back to King's Landing.
I'm not abandoning my army. - You're the
Commander, not a damn infantry man.
These fuckers are about to slomp us.
We can hold them off.
Dracarys!
Hold the line!
-Archers. -Archers.
Archers, follow me!
Get in line!
Nock!
Loose!
- Qyburn's Scorpion is over there.
- Go get it then.
I can't shoot with one hand.
Come on!
Where are you?
Your people do not know how to fight.
Take cover!
Come on, you fucker.
Dracarys!
Flee, you idiot.
Come on, boy. Come on!
You f--
You fucking idiot.
Subtitle by: No One